Professional Profile

Talented Software Engineer with a large experience in the Brazilian Industry, mostly at the Entertainment and Oil & Gas field. Dedicated, patient and creative professional with passion to solve new and hard problems. Also, is known by his self-organization, quick adaptation to new work process, programming languages tools and software applications.

Education

 $M.Sc., Computer\ Science/Visual\ Computing\ -\ Universidade\ Federal\ Fluminense\ -\ 2013$

GPA: 8.6/10.0

Courses Included: Computer Graphics; Multimedia Systems; Algorithm Optimization; Parallel Algorithms;

Data Structures

Relevant Experience

Apr 2013 - Current Job Researcher - EMC - BRDC Center - Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

http://www.emc.com

Summary: Provide new technologies to the Oil & Gas market focused on Big Data and

Analytics research. As a researcher I am responsible for proposing and develop

projects that will optimize the Oil & Gas Process using Big Data and EMC

technologies such as Isilon and Greenplum.

Dec 2012 - Apr 2013 Researcher Intern - Schlumberger - BGDC Center - Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

http://www.slb.com

Summary: Create solutions to the SLB's Petrel Software for Seismic Interpretation. As a

researcher, I developed and optimized Petrel's signal filter algorithms used to manipulate the data of seismic cubes. I used GPU Programming languages such as NVidia's Cuda to parallelize it and obtain a better performance of these algorithms

May 2012 - Oct 2012 Game Developer - Nano Studio - Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

http://www.nanogames.com.br / http://www.favelawars.com

Summary: Develop games for mobile and web platforms. My job included most of the game

developing areas like AI, UI, gameplay and others. The project o took part of is called Favela Wars. It is a turn based strategy game set at Rio de Janeiro in a near

future. It is already released to web/facebook platform.

Mar 2011 - Oct 2011 C#/Unity3D Developer - Brazilian Navy - Niterói, Brazil

http://www.mar.mil.br

summary: Create serious games to help improving sailors' skills. The project I've worked

focused on creating a new bridge simulator using current computer graphics capabilities. I was responsible for the general AI inside of the simulation and the UI.

Oct 2010 - Mar 2010 Software Engineer - ADDLabs - Niterói, Brazil

http://www.addlabs.uff.br

Summary: Plan and Implement aplications to the Oil Industry Using Artificial Intelligence

Techniques and Numerical Methods. All systems were implemented in C/C++, Oracle and Microsoft Foundation Class Library(MFC). I was responsible for both front-end and back-end parts of the implementation, bug fixes, backup procedures, version control using SVN, meeting customers and define requirements of the

software, provide support to other members of the team.

Publications/Presentations

A Parallel Fipa Architecture Based on GPU for Games and Real Time
 Simulations

 Mapping a Path-Finding Multiagent System based on Fipa
 Specification to GPU Architectures
 ICEC 2012
 Bremen, Germany
 SBGames 2011
 Salvador, Brazil

Mapping Multiagent Systems based on Fipa Specification to GPU
 Architectures
 Videojogos 2010
 Lisboa, Portugal

Main Technical Skills

Programming Languages C/C++, C#, Java, Cuda, Shell Script, Javascript

Tools Visual Studio, XCode, Unity3D, Postgres, SVN, Git

Platforms Windows, Linux, Mac, iPhone

Methodologies Scrum

More Information

- Personal Website/Portifolio: http://www.ic.uff.br/~lguilherme
- Linkedin: http://br.linkedin.com/in/luizgosantos/en
- Academic Advisor contacts are also available upon request